(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-08-09T09:55:40.070399",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
夢は見るものじゃない 叶えるものだよ
Dreams aren't just things to see, they're things to make come true!
輝きたい衝動に素直でいようよ
Let's be true to our impulse to shine!
スタートライン！
Start Line!
もし君が立ち止まる迷う日は
Should you ever stop and feel lost,
瞳閉じてココロの声を聞いて
close your eyes and listen to your heart's voice.
諦めないその言葉が道になる
“Never give up”—those words will light your way.
あの日見た景色目指して進もう
Let's press onward toward the scenery we saw that day!
誰かの真似なんて退屈なだけさ
Mimicking someone else is just so boring;
ひとりひとり違うから奇跡 一緒に飛ぼう
our unique differences are miracles—let's take flight together!
夢は見るものじゃない
Dreams aren't just things to see,
叶えるものだよ
they're things to make come true!
輝きたい衝動に素直でいようよ
Let's be true to our impulse to shine!
後悔なんて絶対に君には似合わない
Regret is definitely something that doesn't suit you,
限りのない情熱で飛び越えていこう
so let's leap across with endless passion!
スタートライン！
Start Line!
今はまだ届かない憧れも
Even the aspirations that don't reach yet,
明日こそは届くと信じていよう
let's believe they'll reach us tomorrow.
スタートライン！
Start Line!
頑張れの言葉のお守りを抱いて
Embracing the protective amulet of "Go for it!"
泣かないと見上げた空が笑う
don't cry—the sky you look up to will smile.
間違いや失敗は成功のチャンス
Mistakes and failures are chances for success;
ひとつひとつ積み上げるように挑戦しよう
let's take on the challenge, building it up one by one!
誰にも負けたくない本気の数だけ
For every earnest moment we refuse to lose to anyone,
汗と涙と絆を希望に変えて
turning sweat, tears, and bonds into hope,
ゴールはきっとずっと遠くの方だよ
the goal is surely far, far in the distance,
光を手放すように繋いでいこう
so let's keep connecting it as if letting go of light.
未知数の向こう側に本当の私がいる
On the other side of the unknown is my true self;
内なる羽根を広げて高く高く舞い上がれ
spread your inner wings and soar high, high up!
スタートライン！
Start Line!
きらめきの数だけ誰かがidol
For every sparkle, someone becomes an idol;
誇り高く麗しく大志を抱け
hold lofty and magnificent ambitions!
スタートライン！
Start Line!
さあ顔を上げてチャンスが待ってる！
Now look up, your chance is waiting!
もう少しだけ長く 夢を見たかった
I wanted to dream just a little longer.
思ってたより早く 訪れた現実の朝
The reality of morning came sooner than I thought.
遠く離れた場所 反対もされたね
A place far away, and I even faced opposition.
それでも電話越し 届けてくれた青空
Even so, you reached through the phone with a blue sky.
あの場所へと 辿り着くまで
Until I reach that place,
何度雨にぬれても
no matter how many times I get soaked in the rain,
丘を越えるとき 両手いっぱい 花咲き誇るように
when crossing the hill, may flowers bloom in full across both hands.
簡単には帰れない あなたの腕の中
I can't easily return to your arms.
心配しなくても大丈夫 仲間も出来たよ
Don't worry, I'm fine, I even made friends.
ずっと一人で描いてた夢を
The dream I had always drawn alone,
あなたが叶えてくれて
you made it come true.
ありがとうって伝えたいの
I want to say "thank you"
この歌うたう様に
as if singing this song.
夕暮れの空に
In the twilight sky,
夢だけ抱え 立っている
I stand, holding only my dreams.
何よりも大切なあなたと 交わした約束
The promise we made, more precious than anything,
心の奥一番の支えになっているから
has become my deepest support in my heart.
光の糸辿れば 浮かぶよ あなたの顔が
Following the thread of light, your face floats up.
虹の始まる場所は 雲の下 輝いている
Where the rainbow begins, shining beneath the clouds—
後悔なんて絶対
Regrets? Absolutely not!
君には似合わない
They don't suit you.
限りのない情熱で 飛び越えていこう
Let's leap over them with endless passion.
坂を上げて
Raise the slope,
チャンスが待ってる
and a chance is waiting!
はーい！
Hi!
Ioforia!
Obisa, halo!
Obisa, hello!
Aku Airani Iofi, atau Iofi dari Hololive Indonesia!
I'm Airani Iofi, or Iofi from Hololive Indonesia!
Hai! Dan ini tahu nggak?
Hi! And you know what?
Pertama kali aku 3D birthday guys, guys! Welcome to Iofi's Galaxy Ticket! Hai!
This is my first time having a 3D birthday, guys! Welcome to Iofi's Galaxy Ticket! Hi!
So, by the way, here's the hashtag, so sitop... eeh, sitop, omedetou gozaimasu!
So, by the way, here's the hashtag... um, sitop... eh, sitop, congratulations!
Hai, eee...曲名は「スタートライン」！
Hi, um... the song title is "Start Line"!
The first song is "Start Line." I really, really love this song.
And I really love them... the meaning behind the songs.
And I really love the meaning behind the song.
So if you can, you can just search up the song later, okay?
Jadi, aku pilih ini karena... uh, punya suka bangetlah dari judulnya.
So, I chose this because... uh, I really, really love the title.
Kayak, wah, start line! Start pertama kali!
Like, wow, start line! The very first start!
Nah, begitu, gimana? Suka? Ada yang tahu lagunya? Ah, tahu, ada tahu!
Well, what do you think? Do you like it? Did anyone know the song? Ah, you knew it, you knew it!
Iwa, makasih! Halo! Dan, karena 3D birthday, lihatlah stage-nya!
Yay, thank you! Hello! And since it's a 3D birthday, look at the stage!
Stage-nya bagaimana, sayo?
How's the stage, everyone?
Wah, hero, hero!
Wow, amazing, amazing!
So today, I went worldwide with the theme today.
And actually, I have a lot of guest, guest in it! Mada, mada irun desu kedo... etto, chinamini ne...
And actually, I have a lot of guests in it! There are still more, but... um, by the way...
Ettot... Tada!
Um... Tada!
Apa ini? Ada palet! Jadi, dari sini aku mau ngumpulin warna-warna dari semua guest ya.
What is this? There's a palette! So, from here, I want to collect colors from all the guests, yeah.
Ah, dan, mau, yang lain, warna, itu... to-to-to... to, or least, own color dulu, kan? Wait, ne... oshi... oshi... ok! Tada!
Ah, and also, other colors, um... let's color my own first, right? Wait, um... oshi... oshi... ok! Tada!
Ugh, gila, ini yang pertama kali adalah warna yang punya Yopi!
Ugh, crazy, the very first one is the color that belongs to Iopi!
Jadi, nanti kalau guest-nya ada, nanti akan bertambah! Wah, we're gonna collect cool- collect colors from each member. I wonder what happened.
So later when the guests are here, it will grow! We're gonna collect colors from each member. I wonder what happens.
Mm, ini kalau... asuma-tara, nani ga iru no kana?
Mm, if this... once they gather, what's gonna be there?
Itu adalah, senang-senang di-keep dulu, ya!
That's something to look forward to, so keep it in mind, yeah!
Are you guys ready for the next song? Ready? Ready? Kalian siap? Kalian siap? Siap, kan? Okay! Jadi, kita langsung ke lagu berikutnya.
Are you guys ready for the next song? Ready? Ready? Are you guys ready? Are you guys ready? Are you ready? Okay! So let's go straight to the next song.
Ja, kiite kudasai.
Now, please listen.
Anata no utahime.
Your Diva.
この家のこのパソコンが 私の新しい居場所なの。
This PC in this house is my new place to be.
今日からはあなたがご主人さま 絶対に大切にしてね。
From today you are my master, so treat me very well.
ちょっと！何にするの！こんな卑猥な歌詞を歌わせないで
Hey! What are you doing?! Don't make me sing such lewd lyrics!
寂しくなくて切ない一人の夜には
In a lonely and bittersweet night alone...
消したい言葉を探して
searching for words I want to erase,
秘密のドアを抜け出して here we go
sneaking out through a secret door, here we go!
oh yeah oh yeah
目の前の扉を開ければ
If you open the door right in front of you,
そう、終わり側のない夜への始まりだ
yes, it's the beginning of a night with no end.
気球状のフロアの影から
From the shadow of the balloon-shaped floor,
四次元への旅が始まるよ
a journey to the fourth dimension begins.
流星の箱舟に乗って
Riding in a shooting star's ark,
さあ時空旅行へと進んでいくのだから
come on, we're heading into a space-time journey.
天気予報は当てにならないから
Weather forecasts can't be relied upon,
気の向くまま all right
so wherever the mood takes us, all right!
today is all night be
funky funky funky night
you & i be together
today is all night be
funky funky funky night
you & i funky night
あげてきな dance dance
Let's pump it up, dance, dance!
君の瞳から輝く金流星が
Golden shooting stars shining from your eyes,
秘密のドアを抜け出して here we go
sneaking out through a secret door, here we go!
oh yeah oh yeah
shake shake 今夜は止まらない
shake shake, tonight won't stop,
だから今度は oh 夢の中
so now, oh, inside a dream.
ミラーボールが回りまわる hurry up
The disco ball is spinning round, hurry up!
oh yeah oh yeah
君に出会えて喜び
The joy of meeting you,
いつもいつまでも忘れないよ
I will never forget, always and forever.
私はまだ満足してない
I am not satisfied yet,
あなたの歌を全部歌うまでは
until I sing all of your songs.
私にもっと歌わせて
Let me sing even more,
世界であなただけの歌姫なの
I am the only songstress for you in the world.
寂しくなくて切ない一人の夜には
In a lonely and bittersweet night alone...
消したい言葉を探して
searching for words I want to erase,
秘密のドアを抜け出して here we go
sneaking out through a secret door, here we go!
oh yeah oh yeah
目の前の扉を開ければ
If you open the door right in front of you,
そう、終わり側のない夜への始まりだ
yes, it's the beginning of a night with no end.
気球状のフロアの影から
From the shadow of the balloon-shaped floor,
四次元への旅が始まるよ
a journey to the fourth dimension begins.
流星の箱舟に乗って
Riding in a shooting star's ark,
さあ時空旅行へと進んでいくのだから
come on, we're heading into a space-time journey.
天気予報は当てにならないから
Weather forecasts can't be relied upon,
気の向くまま all right
so wherever the mood takes us, all right!
today is all night be
funky funky funky night
you & i be together
today is all night be
funky funky funky night
you & i funky night
思い返したら 多かったのさ
Looking back, there were so many things
君に貰ってばかりだったね
It was all things I received from you
不安が巡って 頭から離れない
Anxiety swirls around, not leaving my mind
そんなこと知らずに 夜は更けてく
Without knowing that, the night deepens
いつかは日はね 登ってしまうから
Someday the sun will rise after all
永遠はないけど
Though there is no eternity
それでもあすに願ってる
Still, I wish upon tomorrow
here i am ここにいるんだ
Here I am, I'm right here
私を忘れないでね
Please don't forget me
here i am ここにいるんだ
Here I am, I'm right here
今日もずっとそばにいる
Today too, I'll always be by your side
季節は巡り 時が過ぎてもさ
Even as seasons turn and time passes by
私 変わらずに 君を想ってるよ
I still think of you, unchanged
aku di sini ここにいるんだ
Aku di sini, I'm right here
私を忘れないでね
Please don't forget me
aku di sini ここにいるんだ
Aku di sini, I'm right here
今日もずっとそばにいる
Today too, I'll always be by your side
here i am 星の中から
Here I am, from among the stars
aku di sini, cepatlah temukanku
Aku di sini, find me quickly
here i am, i am here waiting for you
今日もずっとそばにいる
Today too, I'll always be by your side
aku di sini
いつかは日はね 登ってしまうから
Someday the sun will rise after all
永遠はないけど
Though there is no eternity
それでもあすに願ってる
Still, I wish upon tomorrow
here i am ここにいるんだ
Here I am, I'm right here
私を忘れないでね
Please don't forget me
here i am ここにいるんだ
Here I am, I'm right here
今日もずっとそばにいる
Today too, I'll always be by your side
秘密のドアを開けてきて here we go
Open the secret door, here we go
shake! shake! 今夜は止まらない
Shake! Shake! Tonight won't stop
秘密のドアを開けてきて
Open the secret door
shake! shake! 今夜は止まらない
Shake! Shake! Tonight won't stop
Hoo! Kembali lagi!
Hoo! Back again!
Halo semuanya!
Hello everyone!
Tadi tidak ya, apa? Tadi ini, 'Anata no Tame ni' and 'Shake it!' Thank you!
That wasn't bad, right? That was 'Anata no Tame ni' and 'Shake it!' Thank you!
Oh, tadi ne, 'Anata no Tame ni' chou enshutsu wa aru n da kedo...
Oh, earlier, there was a cool staging for 'Anata no Tame ni'...
Wakatta hito iru no kana? Ah, iru? Hontoni? Arigatou!
Did anyone notice? Ah, did you? Really? Thank you!
Arigatou ne. Maa, kyonen mitai ni ippai shuwa wa denakute mo, chotto shuwa ga haitte tte, minna wakatteru? Arigatou!
Thank you. Even without as many sign language moves as last year, did you notice the little bit of sign language included? Thank you!
De wa, aratamete, hi guys! I'm Iofi, thank you! It's so nice to meet you again!
So, once again, hi guys! I'm Iofi, thank you! It's so nice to meet you again!
Ah, hontoni ne, minna hontoni arigatou! Itsumo ouen shite kureて arigatou.
Ah, truly, thank you so much everyone! Thank you for always supporting me.
So... I have, I still have a lot of special program!
So... I have, I still have a lot of special programs!
So, after this, there will be, oh, guest appear! There's going to be a guest appear!
So, after this, there will be, oh, a guest appearance! There's going to be a guest appearance!
Dan bisa jadi, jangan kemana-mana. Tetap di sana, kita akan meluncur ke guest appear!
So don't go anywhere. Stay right there, we're heading over to the guest appearance!
Are you guys ready? Ready? Okay!
Here we go! Let's go!
止まらない未来を目指して
Aiming for an unstoppable future,
ゆずれない願いを抱きしめて
Embracing an unyielding wish
海のの色が紅く染まっていく 無重力状態
The sea colors turn crimson, a weightless state
このまま風にさらわれたい
I want to be swept away by the wind just like this
いつも跳べないハードルを 負けない気持ちでクリアしてきたけど
Always clearing unjumpable hurdles with an undefeated spirit, but
出し切れない実力は誰のせい?
Whose fault is it that I can't show my full strength?
止まらない未来を目指して ゆずれない願いを抱きしめて
Aiming for an unstoppable future, embracing an unyielding wish
色褪せない心の地図 光にかざそう
Let's hold our unfading heart maps up to the light
どれだけ泣ければ 朝に出逢えるの
How much do I need to cry to meet the morning?
止まらない未来を目指して ゆずれない願いを抱きしめて
Aiming for an unstoppable future, embracing an unyielding wish
色褪せない心の地図 光にかざそう
Let's hold our unfading heart maps up to the light
どれだけ泣けば 朝に出逢えるの
How much must I cry until I can meet the morning?
孤独な夜 初めて限界を感じた日
The lonely night, the day I first felt my limits.
きっと恋に落ちるのは まばたきみたいな
Surely, falling in love is like a blink,
一瞬の情熱だけど 愛に続く坂道で
instant passion, but on the road of continuing love,
強さを覚えたい
I want to remember strength.
止まらない未来を 夢見て
Dreaming of an unstoppable future,
口を閉ざし 瞳を輝かせてきたけれど
I closed my mouth and made my eyes shine, but
負けない気持ちで 繰り出してきたけれど
keeping an undefeatable spirit, I kept pushing through, but
スタートラインに立つ度に
whenever I stand at the starting line,
怯えていた
I was frightened.
止まらない未来を描いて 腕を伸ばし心を開いて
Sketching an unstoppable future, stretching out my arms, opening my heart,
止まらない未来を目指して 譲れない願いを抱きしめて
aiming at the unstoppable future, embracing my unwavering wish,
色褪せない心の地図 光にかざそう
let's hold up the unfading map of our hearts to the light.
止まらない未来を夢見て 口を閉ざし瞳を輝かせていた
Dreaming of an unstoppable future, closing my mouth with shining eyes...
止まらない未来を描いて 腕を伸ばし心を開いて
Sketching an unstoppable future, stretching out my arms, opening my heart,
止まらない未来を目指して 譲れない願いを抱きしめて
aiming at the unstoppable future, embracing my unwavering wish,
止まらない未来を目指して 譲れない願いを目指して
aiming at the unstoppable future, aiming at my unwavering wish,
譲れない願いを抱きしめて 瞳を...
embracing my unwavering wish, with my eyes...
揺るわされない
Indestructible
心の地図
map of the heart,
光にかざそう
let's hold it up to the light.
はあ、来てくれてありがとう！
Ah, thank you for coming!
晴れてさ、お誕生日おめでとう！
Finally, Happy Birthday!
うわあ！嬉しい！
Whoa! I'm so happy!
よね、さっきの曲、「譲れない願い」っていう曲でしたね。
Right, that previous song was "Yuzurenai Negai."
えっとね、この曲を歌いたいっていうのはね、どうしてもどうしても譲れない願いがあるんですよ、イフィは。
Um, you see, I really, really had an unwavering wish to sing this song, Iofi did.
何が譲れなかったの？
What couldn't you compromise on?
多分ね、今回がひとつのステージ、こうやってソラ姉と一緒に初めての... ああね、そうなんだね。
Maybe, you know, this time as one stage, doing this for the first time with Sora-nee... Ah, right, that's right.
そう、ずっとやりたかったんだよね。
Yeah, I've always wanted to do it.
でね、今日二人で... えと、いや本当にね、ちょっと緊張したんだけど
And you know, today the two of us... um, well actually, we were a bit nervous, but...
大丈夫だった？
Were you okay?
いやもう全然よかった！すごいよかった！
Yeah, it was totally fine! It was amazing!
ありがとう！なんかこうちょっとプルプルしてて...
Thank you! I was kind of shaking a bit...
ねえ、どうしよう、めちゃくちゃ楽しかった！ 本当？うん！
Hey, what should I do, it was so much fun! Really? Yeah!
ありがとう！嬉しい！
Thank you! I'm so happy!
でね、そら姉ね、ステージね、そら姉の映画いうんです。
And you know, Sora-nee, on stage, Sora-nee's movie...
あ、ちょっと見えたよ。
Ah, I could see it a bit.
え、見えた？うん。
Eh, you saw it? Yeah.
え、じゃあちょっとどこかな... どこかな...
Eh, then where could it be... where could it be...
こっちだったっか？
Was it this way?
こっちだったかな？ あ、いた！あれだ！
Was it this way? Ah, there! That's it!
そうね、このステージもね、そら姉がいるしね。
That's right, Sora-nee is on this stage too, you know.
ねー、二人で仲良しだよ！
Yeah, we're good friends, aren't we!
仲良しだよ！ねえ！
We're good friends! Yeah!
でね、コメントのみんなはちょっと見えた！っていう人がいるから... 見えた？みんな見えた？
And you know, since some people in the comments were saying "I can see it!"... You saw it? Did everyone see it?
あ、見えたって。
Ah, they saw it.
すごい、一瞬だったもんね。
Amazing, it was just for a split second, wasn't it.
いやでもね、それだけ私たちのことしっかり見てくれたっていうことだよ。
But you know, that just means you watched us very carefully.
ありがとうね！
Thank you so much!
ちょっとね、イフィにね、プレゼントがあるんだ！
You know, Iofi has a present!
なんだろう？
What could it be?
なんだろう？なんだろうねー。
What could it be? I wonder what it is.
これだ！
This is it!
あれね、実はね、イフィ持てるんだ。
That, actually, Iofi can hold it.
え？ ちょっとね、あれにぴったりのもの。
Eh? Something that fits that.
うわあ！ ちょっと... ね、そら姉の色をぬってみようかなー。
Whoa! Let's try painting Sora-nee's color.
いいよ！ いいの？
Sure! Really?
うわー！どうかな？
Whoa! How is it?
うわー！増えた！ 増えたよー！
Whoa! It increased! It increased!
やった！ ねえ！ ありがとうね！
Yay! Hey! Thank you!
いや、こちらこそ！ じゃあこれは閉めておこうかな。
No, thank you! Well then, I'll close this up.
ね、そうだね。
Yeah, that's right.
大事だからね。
Because it's important.
まあ、ちょっとしまっちゃおうかな。
Wait, let's put it away.
あ、すでにしまっちゃってたわ。
Oh, it's already put away.
さあ、これからもまだまだということで
Now, from here on, we still have a lot more, so
はい、また会おうかなと、うん、ゲットパートもまだまだ続くからね。
Yes, I hope we'll meet again, and the ticket part will continue a bit more.
はーい、じゃあねー、みんな！
Haaay, bye-bye everyone!
じゃあねー、おめでとう！ありがとう！
Bye-bye, congratulations! Thank you!
「俺んとこ来ないか？」
"Wanna come to my place?"
ワンナイト・カーニバル 胸の奥 zuki-zuki と音立てる angel
One night carnival, my heart is throbbing loudly, angel
「とにかくもう学校や家には帰りたくない」 angel
"Either way, I don't want to go back home or to school," angel
退屈に怯えてたのさ 夜の闇に逃げ込んだ angel
Afraid of boredom, we escaped into the night's darkness, angel
「俺達まるで捨て猫みたい」 angel
"Just like stray cats," angel
can you master baby? master baby! can't you master baby? master baby!
瞬きもせずに 俺たちは 光の渦に巻き込まれていく
In the blink of an eye, we were sucked into a whirlpool of light
雲の隙間に 照らせ 青白き月よ 照らせ
Shine out from between the clouds, pallid moon, shine out
星が瞬く distance さみしがり屋達の伝説 さ
Stars sparkling in the distance, the legend of lonely people,
one night carnival fun fun
風に香る tactics が 俺の胸を締めつける
Your fragrant tactics riding on the wind press hard upon my heart,
angel
「今 だけ は 悲しい 嘘 聴き たく ない よ」
"I don't want to hear any sad lies right now,"
angel
can you master baby? master baby!
can't you master baby? master baby!
can you master baby? be my baby!!
can't you master baby? so long...
「俺達がやさぐれた事に理由なんて無かったよ、ただ少しだけ不器用だったのかも知れない」
"There was no reason for us to act up, maybe we were just a little awkward."
恋しているのさ この夜に恋しているのさ
In love, we are in love tonight
やがて海が見える さみしがり屋達の伝説 さ
The sea's finally in sight, the legend of lonely people,
one night carnival fun fun
“あの頃の俺達、闇の中じゃなくちゃ夢見られなかった。あのミラーボールみたいに明るくて真円なお月様に憧れただけサ。行こうぜ、ピリオドの向こうへ．．．”
"We couldn't dream unless we were in the darkness back then. We only yearned for that bright, perfectly round moon like a mirrorball. Let's go, beyond the period..."
もうすぐ海が見える さみしがり屋達の伝説 さ
We'll soon see the sea, the legend of lonely people,
one night carnival fun fun
one night carnival
oh wrong
let's get free...
風に香る tactics が 俺の胸を締めつける angel
Your fragrant tactics riding on the wind press hard upon my heart, angel
「夜の闇に逃げ込んだ俺たちは…」
"We who escaped into the night's darkness..."
can you master baby? master baby!
can't you master baby? master baby!
can't you master baby? so long...
瞬きもせずに 俺たちは 光の渦に巻き込まれていく
In the blink of an eye, we were sucked into a whirlpool of light
雲の隙間に 照らせ 青白き月よ 照らせ
Shine out from between the clouds, pallid moon, shine out
星が瞬く distance さみしがり屋達の伝説 さ
Stars sparkling in the distance, the legend of lonely people,
one night carnival fun fun
恋しているのさ この夜に恋しているのさ
In love, we are in love tonight
やがて海が見える さみしがり屋達の伝説 さ
The sea's finally in sight, the legend of lonely people,
one night carnival fun fun
寂しがり屋たちの伝説さ ワンナイト・カーニバル
The legend of lonely people, one night carnival
あの頃の俺たち 闇の中じゃなくちゃ夢見られなかった
Back then, we couldn't dream unless we were in the darkness
あのミラーボールみたいに 明るくて真円なお月様に憧れただけさ
We only yearned for that bright, perfectly round moon like a mirrorball
行こうぜ ピリオドの向こうへ…
Let's go, beyond the period...
もうすぐ海が見える
We'll soon see the sea
寂しがり屋たちの伝説さ ワンナイト・カーニバル
The legend of lonely people, one night carnival
ワンナイト・カーニバル
One night carnival
「俺んとここないか？」
"Wanna come to my place?"
ワンナイト・カーニバル 胸の奥 zuki-zukiと音立ててる
"One night carnival, my heart throbs deeply,"
angel
「とにかくもう 学校や家には帰りたくない」
"Anyway, I don't want to go back to school or home."
angel
退屈に怯えてたのさ 夜の闇に逃げ込んだ
"Afraid of boredom, we escaped into the dark night."
angel
「俺達まるで捨て猫みたい」
"We're just like stray cats."
angel
can you master baby? master baby!
can't you master baby? master baby!
can't you master baby so long...
あけましておめでとう、イオフィ、オフィ！
"Happy New Year, Iofi, Iofi!"
ありがとう！
"Thank you!"
お前ちっちゃいな！
"You're so small!"
ちっちゃいよ、俺も。
"I'm small too."
なんか連れ去られた宇宙人みたいだよね本当に。
"You really look like an abducted alien."
話さないでくださいよ！
"Please don't bring that up!"
OGAだって特にね！
"Especially you, Oga!"
あらあら、あらあら、ちっちゃいね。
"My, my, how small."
いや、自分もちっちゃくないよ！
"Hey, I'm not small either!"
いや、どっかで聞いたことあるね、ちっちゃくないよ。
"I feel like I've heard that somewhere before."
ポケットサイズ！
"Pocket-sized!"
ポケットサイズってちっちゃいじゃん！だいぶちっちゃいじゃん！
"Pocket-sized means it's small! That's tiny!"
とりま、そろそろサングラス外していい？
"Anyway, can we take off our sunglasses soon?"
うん、なんかね、せっかくだからちょっとお顔を見せたいし。
"Yeah, since it's an occasion, we want to show our faces."
そうね、じゃあ外しか、はい。
"That's right, then let's take them off, okay."
ええと、じゃあ準備いい？
"Um, then are you ready?"
はい。
"Yes."
はい、せーの、はっ！
"Ready, set, go!"
まあやっぱね、我々ともなると、こう手を使わずにサングラスを取ることも可能になってきたからね。
"Well, as expected of us, we've reached a point where we can take off our sunglasses without using our hands."
てなわけで
"So,"
改めて、え、ほぼ同期、荒咬オウガです。
"once again, I'm Aragami Oga."
え、ほぼ同期、影山シエンです。こんにちはー！
"Um, I'm Kageyama Shien. Hello!"
よっしゃ、よっしゃ。
"Alright, alright."
ありがとう！
"Thank you!"
いや呼んでくれてありがとうね、本当に。
"Thanks for inviting us, really."
まさか、あの、ワンナイト・カーニバル歌うとはちょっと思わなかったけどね。
"I honestly didn't expect us to sing 'One Night Carnival'."
ちょっとね、この曲ね、
"You know, this song..."
ラップ以外ってさ、普通に歌いたいだけなんだよ。
"Except for the rap part, I just want to sing normally."
ああ、本当に？
"Oh, really?"
そう。特にラップいんの、じゃあ？
"Yeah. Do you especially need the rap, then?"
ない。
"No."
じゃあ誰でもよかった？
"Then anyone would do?"
誰でもよかったわけではない！
"It's not that anyone would do!"
じゃあ逆言うと、俺たちと歌いたかったんだ？
"Then conversely, you wanted to sing with us?"
いや、だからと言って、誰でもよかったわけではない！
"Well, that doesn't mean just anyone was fine!"
いや、じゃあ逆言うと、俺たちと歌いたかったんだ？へえー。
"Well, to put it the other way around, you wanted to sing with us? Huh."
いや、うん、別になんかそれだけを歌いたいっていうわけでもない、ない、ないんだけどね。
"Well, um, it's not like I specifically wanted to sing only that."
まあまあ、とにかくおめでとう！本当にね、おめでとう！
"Well, anyway, congratulations! Really, congratulations!"
なんちゃいになったの？
"How old did you turn?"
なんちゃい？ええとね、ピーってなっちゃう。
"How old? Um, it gets beeped out."
ああ、そうそう、そんなに。
"Ah, right, right, not that much."
そこは、そこはじゃあ伏せとこう。
"Let's keep that part under wraps."
でね、実はね、今日ね、みんなからね、ちょっとペイントね、色を集めてるんですよ。
"And actually, today we're collecting paint and colors from everyone."
おおー、色？
"Oh, colors?"
そう、色ね。
"Yes, colors."
だれだれ？お、こんなところに絵の具が！
"Who's that? Oh, paint in a place like this!"
じゃ、ペイントいたんだけど、ちちよ、俺の爪の垢をお返しします！
"Well, I painted, here, I'll give you the dirt from under my fingernails in return!"
俺の爪の垢をあげる。はい！
"I'll give you the dirt from my fingernails. Here!"
おお！オガの色が追加されたの汁です！
"Ooh! This is Oga's color added to the palette!"
ああ、やった！じゃあ、シエンはどっかに出して。
"Ah, yay! Then Shien, get it out from somewhere."
俺、尻からしか色出さないからさ。じゃあ、尻、尻、尻！
"I only produce colors from my butt. So, butt, butt, butt!"
本当にちょっと、絵面が、絵面がやばいことになるから。
"Seriously, the visuals are going to get dangerous."
まあ、あの、お食事中の方ちょっとね、見ないように。いくぞ！
"Well, those who are eating, please try not to look. Here we go!"
はい！うわっ！待って待って、待てって！うわっ！
"Hah! Woah! Wait, wait, hold on! Woah!"
出る！
"It's coming out!"
出た！劇的的に！
"It came out! Dramatically!"
よかったよかった。いや、ちょ、ちょ、やめろ、やめろ、汚ねえ！
"Good, good. Hey, stop, stop, gross!"
絶対汚くない！絶対汚くないです！
"It's definitely not gross! It's definitely not gross!"
影山汁汚くないです！誰がうんちですか！
"Kageyama juice is not gross! Who's poop?!"
あー、じゃ、と、ということでね、もう増えました！
"Ah, s-, s-, so with that, it increased!"
よかった！尻出してよかったわ。
"Great! I'm glad I showed my butt."
うん。はい、ということでね、
"Yeah. So,"
ま、こうね、この後ね、まだまだい、まだまだいるけど、今回はね、このあとめっちゃスペシャルプログラムというのが、あるんですよ！
"Well, like this, after this, there's still more, but this time, after this, there's a super special program!"
スペシャルプログラム、バラエティ！
"Special program, variety!"
ええ、楽しみだね。ということで、またねの準備してるから、ちょっと待ってね。ありがとう！こちらもこそ、またね！ありがとう、またね！
"Yeah, looking forward to it. So, we're getting ready for 'see you later', so please wait. Thank you! Same here, see you later! Thanks, see you!"
はい！ということで、今日はね、の準備もOKなうえで、
"Right! So, today, our preparations are all good,"
今日はゲストを呼ぶかなあ！じゃあ呼びましょう！
"so today we're going to invite guests! Let's call them!"
オッケー、ゲストカモーン！
"Okay, guests, come on!"
ということで今日はね、みんなあ
"So today, everyone..."
今日はね、みんなにね、めちゃくちゃめちゃくちゃの
Today, I'm going to give you super amazing...
おもてなしをするんで、楽しみにしててください。
hospitality, so please look forward to it.
誕生日なのはイオフィなんだけどさ。
Even though it's Iofi's birthday.
そうだね。私たちが、おもてなしをするの！
That's right. We are hosting you!
いや、大丈夫、大丈夫。
No, it's fine, it's fine.
あれ、これさ、関係ないよね、この1、2、3、4、5、6...
Wait, these numbers 1 to 6 don't matter, right?
あれは関係ないよね、たぶん。
Those don't matter, probably.
後ろにはさ、ちゃんと箱があるよ。
There are actually boxes in the back, you know.
そう。後ろにもね、7つぐらいのあの箱があるけど、中身ね、イオフィもさ、ぶっちゃなわかんない。
Right. In the back there are about 7 boxes, but honestly, even Iofi doesn't know what's inside.
え、マジで？
Eh, really?
プレゼントが一般のかも。後ろに行こうかじゃあ。プレゼントいっぱいあるのかもよ？
Maybe it's ordinary gifts. Shall we go to the back? Maybe there are lots of presents!
で、私たちのプレゼントってことじゃない？でも、プレゼントって言ってたような...
So aren't these presents for us? But I thought you said presents...
まあね、中身はね、ちゃん食べられるものなら大丈夫。
Well, as long as the contents are edible, it's fine.
食べれる？食べれない！食べれない！食べれない！待って、待って...
Can we eat it? We can't eat it! Wait, wait...
イオフィがインドネシアからわざわざ持ってきてくれたプレゼントがここにあって...
The presents Iofi went out of her way to bring from Indonesia are right here...
で、うちらはこの1から7を指定して、そう、食べりゃいいじゃん、食べりゃいいんですよ。
So, we specify 1 through 7, and yes, you just eat it! You just eat it.
じゃあ絶対美味しいもんだわ。そうやね！
Then it must be delicious. That's right!
美味しい？美味しい？美味しい、美味しい！
Delicious? Delicious? Delicious, delicious!
え、待って、そこにあるゴミ箱は何だい、イオフィ？
Eh, wait, what's that trash can over there, Iofi?
でね、そう、この左と右もね...
And you see, left and right also...
ゴミ箱、ゴミ箱って...ペール缶？ちょっとね、ちょっとでも食べられないものだったらそこに入れてください。
Trash cans, trash cans... Pail cans? If there's anything you really can't eat, please put it in there.
そう、ここにはね、青色とピンク色があるから、好みの、好みを選んでください。
So, here we have blue and pink, so please choose the one you like.
キイのこの、そんな使い方して...
Polka, using it like that...
いいよ、いいよ、わざわざ可愛くしているから、可愛くしてもらったんだから。
It's fine, since she went out of her way to make it cute, have it made cute.
使ってください！使ってくださーい。可愛くないけどね。
Please use it! Even though it's not cute.
え、でもイオフィがこれは、ベールズに、あるいはベジマイトで...
Eh, but Iofi, is this for Baelz, or Vegemite?
あー！間違ったの、待って！いや、待って、うわっ！
Ah! Wrong one, wait! No, wait, woah!
一番美味しいもんですのよ！だからその企画やったのかこれです。
It's the most delicious thing! That's why we did this project with this.
よかったね。じゃあ箱全部食べて...じゃあ全部で。
That's great. Then eat all the boxes... So all of them.
食べます！全部で。食べまーす！食べまーす！
We'll eat! All of them. Let's eat! Let's eat!
じゃあポルカ行こうかな。あ、ポルカからも。ポルカも行こうかな。
Then Polka, let's go. Ah, from Polka. Polka, let's go.
行くからだってね、目の前にあるもんの箱が、このナンバーワン！ナンバーワン？
Because you see, right in front of us, the box is number one! Number one?
ナンバーワンがあるからね。ナンバーワン？
Because there's number one. Number one?
え、イオフィ、ナンバーワンはどんな感じなんすか？匂いがする？
Eh, Iofi, what is number one like? Does it smell?
いや、正直ね、わかんないの。あれ？全然匂いはしない。匂いしないね。
Well, honestly, I don't know. Huh? It doesn't smell at all. No smell.
じゃあナンバーワン！いよいよナンバーワンオープン！たーん！
Then number one! Finally number one open! Ta-da!
なにこれ？
What is this?
これね、ブルム。ブルム？ブルム？
This is Brem. Brem? Brem?
で、一応ね、これおかしなのだから...美味しいそうじゃん！
And, well, since this is a snack... It looks delicious!
あ、わかる？あ、わかる？じゃあちょっといただきます。あ、うどん？
Ah, do you know? Ah, do you know? Then let me try some. Ah, udon?
どうも。うん、うん、うん。どう？どう？一応ね、イオフィは苦手なのよ。
Hello. Mhm, mhm. How is it? How? Actually, Iofi dislikes it.
え？苦手なの？あ、苦手なんだ。
Eh? You dislike it? Ah, you dislike it.
え、美味しい？美味しい？あ、でも他のみんなもそれ気になるんだったら、あの、どうぞ。
Eh, delicious? Delicious? Ah, but if the others are curious, please go ahead.
じゃあ食べますわ。なんだこれ、甘いけど...甘いんだ。いただきます。
Then I'll eat it. What is this, it's sweet... but it's sweet. Itadakimasu.
なんかこうあんまりしょっぱみもづく？
Somehow it has some saltiness too?
あのね、えっと、食べようかな。そう、結構お酒あって...
You see, um, shall I eat it? So, it has quite a bit of alcohol...
日本で言うと、この落花生にちょっと食感が近い。
In Japan, its texture is a bit close to peanuts.
なるほど。そう、これね一応スタッフさんも食べるんですけど、スタッフさんから言うと、なんか甘酒っぽいのもあるっていう。
I see. So, the staff also eat this, but according to the staff, it has a bit of an amazake feel.
はい。ちょっと、さっき、わかるって言ったんだけど、全然嘘でした。
Yes. Earlier I said I knew, but that was a total lie.
全然違うものだった。
It was completely different!
じゃあこれが初めてということでね。初めて。どうだ？
Then this is the first time. First time. How is it?
おいしい？え、なんか不思議だね。甘っ！甘いよね。
Delicious? Eh, it's kind of mysterious. So sweet! It's sweet.
いや、自分的にはこのカサカサの、パサパサ感が、あんまり好きじゃなかったから...
Well, for me, I didn't really like this dry, crumbly texture...
好きじゃないのも持ってくる！そう、好き嫌いガードルがいっぱいあるから...
Bringing things you don't like! That's right, there are so many things you don't like...
好きじゃないのも持ってきてる。おもてなしありがとうございました。
Bringing things you don't like too. Thank you for the hospitality.
じゃあ次行きましょうか。ユキあるから。
Then shall we go to the next? Because Yuki has it.
行くよ！やった！オッケー。
Let's go! Yay! Okay.
好きな数字があるんだ。どんな数字？
There's a number you like. What number?
全然だと思わない？なんでもいいじゃん。
Don't you think it's totally nothing? Anything is fine.
44、46？
44, 46?
誕生日がね、ロンドン、角っぽいからね。角っぽいから6。
Because my birthday is London, it's corner-like. Corner-like is 6.
じゃあ、角っぽいから6をね、お願いします！オープン！
Then, since it's corner-like, 6 please! Open!
え！？なにこれ？
Eh!? What is this?
これキャンディなんすよ キャンディ
This is candy, you know, candy.
タマリンド... 名前でもやばい
Tamarind... Even the name sounds scary.
え、タマリンドは、え...え？
Eh, Tamarind is, uh... eh?
タマリンド？タマリンド食べる
Tamarind? Eat Tamarind.
え、色やばいよ！え、やばくないよ！
Eh, the color is crazy! Eh, it's not crazy!
え、ほんとに、袋は可愛いのに。
Eh, seriously, even though the bag is cute.
ハァイタ！ハァイタ！ハァイタ！ハァイタ！
Haita! Haita! Haita! Haita!
あ、でも、殻があるから、後ろ、あれ、ぐわって
Ah, but it has a shell, so behind, um, riiight
え？もう、とりあえず...
Eh? Well, anyway...
いったら！いったら！いったら！いったら！いったら！
Go for it! Go for it! Go for it!
え、なになに？
Eh, what, what?
ポキポキ？ポキポキ？
Poki poki? Poki poki?
あれ？思ったより...
Huh? More than I thought...
いける？いける？いけそう？大丈夫？え？
Can you? Can you? Looks doable? Are you okay? Eh?
え、大丈夫？
Eh, is it okay?
思ったより全然食べれる！
I can eat it way more than I thought!
え、強い！大丈夫大丈夫！
Eh, strong! It's okay, it's okay!
じゃなくて食レポなんだよ！
Not that, this is a food report!
そうだ。どんな感じかなって。
That's right. Wondering what it feels like.
どんな味？
What kind of taste?
あ、い、いよ？
Ah, g-go ahead?
え、みんな、ちょっとすっぱいのかな？
Eh, everyone, is it a bit sour?
すごいすっぱい！
Super sour!
お菓子なの？これもう、お菓子？
Is it a snack? Is this already a snack?
食べよう、食べてみようね！
Let's eat, let's try eating it!
食べてよ！食べて！
Eat it! Eat!
食べて、食べて！
Eat it, eat it!
なんでボールが2連続...
Why are the balls 2 in a row...
じゃあ、2いこうよ。
Then, let's go with 2.
え？結構好きだよ！
Eh? I quite like it!
ポルカは結構好き。
Polka quite likes it.
おっ？
Oh?
うん、うん、うん。
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
なんか、色の割に
Like, considering the color...
どうですか？
How is it?
どうですか？どうですか？いける？いける？噛める噛める！
How is it? Can you? Can you? You can chew it!
どうですか？
How is it?
ん？なんだこれ？
Hm? What is this?
なんだこれ？
What is this?
まいと、まいと。どうですか？
Maito, maito. How is it?
甘い、甘い！
Sweet, sweet!
ね、甘い、甘いんだ。
See, sweet, it's sweet.
でも、なんか、分かんない、黒豆じゃなくて何て言うんだろこれ？
But, like, I don't know, instead of black beans, what is this called?
はい、コーラみたい。
Yeah, like cola.
コーラ！コーラみたい、はい。
Cola! Like cola, yeah.
コーラよりすっぱい。ね、なんかね、まずい...
Sours than cola. Hey, somehow, tastes bad...
まずい、まずい、まずい。
Bad, bad, bad.
さっきからまずいっぽいのが続いてる
Ever since earlier, bad-tasting things keep continuing.
じゃあ次は私が行こうかな。
Then maybe I'll go next.
え、いく？いく？と、何番いく？何番いく？何番いく？
Eh, going? Going? Wh- which number? Which number?
からの、7、ラッキー7！
From there, 7, Lucky 7!
いいことありそう！
Sounds like good things will happen!
ラッキー7の7で、どうぞ。
With the 7 of Lucky 7, go ahead.
ラッキーかな？
Is it lucky?
なになに？
What what?
え？なにこれ？
Eh? What is this?
おっ、なにこれ？
Oh, what is this?
ワジット、ワジット？
Wajit, Wajit?
一応、まだ...
Well, still...
ワジット！
Wajit!
ワジット、なんか包まれてる。
Wajit, it's wrapped in something.
じゃあ、食べてみます。いただきます。
Well, then, I'll try eating it. Itadakimasu.
どんなんやろ？
What's it like?
どうだ？
How is it?
え、待って、食感的にはたぶんもちっぽいかな？もっちもちで、もっちもちだけど...
Eh, wait, in terms of texture, probably mochi-like? Mochi-mochi, mochi-mochi, but...
でも、外側はすごいサクサクしてて、えー、サクもち？サクもち？
But the outside is super crispy, eh, crispy-mochi? Crispy-mochi?
あ、そのまま、サク、サクって...
Ah, just, crispy, crispy...
普通にスイーツだ。
It's just a normal sweet.
めっちゃ美味しい！
Super delicious!
今んところさ、普通に美味しいよね。
Up to now, it's normally delicious, right?
よかったよ！
That's great!
ね、美味しかったよね。
Yeah, it was delicious.
美味しい、めっちゃ美味しいこれ。ケーキみたいな感じじゃん。
Delicious, super delicious, this. It feels like cake.
じゃあ、もう、なんか、大丈夫なんじゃないかな？
Well then, already, like, it's probably fine, right?
え、だって美味しくないすか？
Eh, because isn't it delicious?
え、めっちゃ美味しくないすか？
Eh, isn't it super delicious?
大丈夫、大丈夫！
It's fine, it's fine!
ベールス、ベールス、ベールス！
Baelz, Baelz, Baelz!
美味しい！美味しい！
Delicious! Delicious!
どこいく？どこいく？
Where to go? Where to go?
4番、お願いします！
Number 4, please!
はい、どん、どん、どん、どん！
Here, don, don, don, don!
おお、バンドレック・バンドゥンだ！
Oh, it's Bandrek Bandung!
そう、これ、バンドレック、バンドレックという
Yes, this, Bandrek, it's called Bandrek
スープには見えるけどね。
It looks like soup though.
名前はかっこいいよ。
The name sounds cool.
香りはなんか、バンドレック、バンドレック。
The scent is like, Bandrek, Bandrek.
どんな匂いする？
What kind of scent does it have?
ちょっと、べ、べちゃん？
Wait, Be- Be-chan?
ちょっとべ、べちゃん、酔っとく？大丈夫？
Wait, Be- Be-chan, getting drunk? Is it okay?
検診、酔っとく？
Medical check, getting drunk?
やっぱ、やっぱ、やっぱ、ちゃんと、あ、いるよ。ちょっと、そっち、そっちに匂いする。
As expected, properly, ah, it's there. A bit, that way, that way it smells.
嘘でしょ？
No way, right?
いや、さすがに...
Well, as expected...
なんか、臭っ？
Somehow, stinky?
くさい？
Stinky?
え？くさい？
Eh? Stinky?
お茶なんじゃん？
Isn't it tea?
お茶とか、くさ、草の匂い？草の匂いがする。
Tea or, stink-, grass smell? It smells like grass.
じゃ、ショット行きますね。
Well then, I'll go for a shot.
あ、はいはい、ショット、ショット、ちょ、いけるよ。
Ah, yes yes, shot, shot, ch-, you can do it.
チョーキット、チョーキット！すごいすごいすごい！
Chōkit, chōkit! Amazing amazing amazing!
いいよ、いいよ、いいよ！
Good, good, good!
あ、あ、はははは！
Ah, ah, hahaha!
大丈夫、バカにすんなれ、大丈夫。
It's fine, don't make fun of it, it's fine.
最初甘いんだけど、最後は辛い！
It's sweet at first, but spicy at the end!
そう！辛い！
That's right! Spicy!
ジンジャードリンクというか、ジンジャー！
Ginger drink, or rather, ginger!
生姜じゃん、生姜だよ！
It's ginger, it's ginger!
喉にやたら高い。
It hits the throat a lot.
ね、喉に、そう、しょうが、生姜！
Yeah, in the throat, that's right, ginger, ginger!
すっごい、全部いっ、全部いった、全部いった。
Super, all went, all went, all went.
全部いったよ、全部いった。
All went, all went.
すごい！
Amazing!
勇者だ！
Hero!
勇者！喉どう？
Hero! How's your throat?
でも、なんか、すっきり。生姜するからね。
But, like, refreshing. Because of the ginger.
物の紹介さえ終われば大丈夫。
As long as the product introduction is done, it's fine.
いや、みんな
Yeah, everyone
じゃ、ヤッピー？
Then, Yappy?
え、ちょっとヤッピーも？
Eh, a bit Yappy too?
うん、ちょっとね、おもてなしとしてさ...
Yeah, a bit, as hospitality...
んー。食べるけどね。
Hmm, I'll eat it, though.
ナンバーに何が入ってるか。わかんない、わかんない。
We don't know what's in the numbers at all.
正直ね、一番苦手なものがここに入ってるから。
Honestly, because the thing I'm worst at is in here.
出て、出て、出てないんだ！
It's not coming out!
みんな、何番ですか？ 教えて。
Everyone, which number is it? Tell me!
えーと…じゃ、じゃ、じゃ、じゃ！ じゃ、5で！
Um... well then, let's go with 5!
5番！
Number 5!
怖いな。5番は…
Scary... Number 5 is...
なんだ、なんだ、なんだ？
What is it, what is it?
ドドル シルサック
[Title: Dodol sirsak]
なんだろうね。甘いです。
I wonder what it is. It's sweet.
え、甘い。ソフト味？
Oh, sweet. Soft flavor?
おかし、おかし。うん。おかし？ おかしい？
Snack? Snack? Hmm. Snack? Weird?
美味しい、ふしぎ、おいしい。
Delicious, weird, delicious.
もち、また、もちっぽいのがね。えっと、日本で言うと羊羹っぽい。
It's mochi... It's kind of like mochi. Like yokan in Japan.
ようかん？ ああ、そうそうそう。
Yokan? Ah, yeah, exactly.
えーと、これフルーツ？ フルーツなんだ。酸わ、酸わソフト味？
Um, is this fruit? It's fruit. Sour... sour soft flavor?
酸味ソフト味って言われても、ちょっとパッとは…酸味って、日本のくだものの酸味ソフト味というものがあって、それでキャンディ…なるほどね。
Even if you say sour soft flavor, it's hard to picture... There are sour soft flavors of Japanese fruits, and so candy... I see.
よかったね。よかったね。フルーツの味。
That's good. That's good. Fruit flavor.
え、ちょっと待って。一番怖いものがまだ2つ残ってるってこと？ おや、おや、おや…
Wait a minute. Does that mean the two scariest things are still left? Oh my, oh my...
ふたり特攻で…え？
Two-person suicide mission... Eh?
チーム戦行く？そう、チーム戦で行きますか。
Team battle? Right, let's do a team battle.
イオフィは？ い、いや…誕生日だから、イオフィ…で、出るも…どっちも来る？どっちも？どっちも食べる？
Iofi? N-No... It's your birthday, Iofi... Are both coming out? Both? Do you eat both?
いや、さすがに…苦手もの残ってないし、どっちも食べるしよ。どっち行く？どっち行く？
No way... Neither of us has any weaknesses left, and we'll eat both. Which way? Which way?
やべえな、どっちがいい？どうする？いや、先輩に任せるわ。
Oh no, which is better? What should I do? No, I'll leave it to my senpai.
あ、でもじゃあ、譲りますよ。そっちに。え、どっちがいい？どっち？
Ah, but then I'll yield. To you. Eh, which is better? Which?
掘り物には肉好き？ 肉が張る？ 本当に譲って大丈夫だったかな？
Do you like meat for excavated items? Meat swells? Was it really okay to yield?
3、3、3で見る？ 3？ せーの！ じゃ、こっちは2だ！
Shall we check 3? 3? Ready, set! Well, this one is 2!
アルバ・パスティレス
[Title: Alba Pastilles]
なに、なに？ これね、アルバパスティレスという、またキャンディーなんだけど。キャンディーだよ。
What, what? This is called Alba Pastilles, another candy. It's candy.
そう、パスタキャンディーって言うと、みんな美味しそうって言うけど…見てみる？
Yeah, when you say pasta candy, everyone says it looks delicious... Shall we take a look?
あ、いいよ。じゃあ、2も見て もいいから。え、2も、そう…じゃあ、それだったら…
Ah, sure. Then you can look at 2 as well. Eh, 2 as well, yeah... well, if that's the case...
ミオピーが嫌いなやつって、すごいやつなんじゃないの？ そうだよね。そうだよね。
Mio-pi's disliked one must be amazing, right? That's right. That's right.
ドリアン キャンディー
[Title: DURIAN Candy]
これ、これ、ドリアンキャンディーだ！ ドリアン！
This is, this is DURIAN Candy! Durian!
そう、えっとね、生のドリアンね、持ってきたかったんだけど、ちょっとさすがにやばいから、キャンディーの方ね、持ってきたの。
Yeah, um, I wanted to bring raw durian, but since it's a bit too extreme, I brought the candy version.
においがそんなに…あ、甘納豆？ じゃあ、ドリアン味なんだ。全然わかんないけどな、においが。全然わかんない。
The smell isn't that... Ah, candied beans? Then it's durian flavor. I don't get the smell at all. I don't get it at all.
え、じゃあ帰ろ？ じゃあ帰る？ 帰んない、帰んない。ちゃんと食べとくか。
Eh, then shall we go home? Shall we go home? We're not going home. We should eat it properly.
じゃあ、じゃあ、先、どうぞ、どうぞ。
Well then, first, go ahead, go ahead.
え、緑の粒。かわいい。
Eh, green grains. Cute.
え、かわいい。それも、粒っぽいのか な？
Eh, cute. Is that also grain-like?
あめ？ あ、どっち？ パキッて…あ、パキッて！ お、これはによい。あ、おおお、すごいね、す、っというかたちの…うん。
Candy? Ah, which? Snap... Ah, snap! Oh, this smells... Ah, wow, it's amazing, a shape that...
なんだ…すーすー系だね。あ、そうそう。ミントっぽい感じ？ いや、すーすーじゃなくて、わたあめは逆にすーすーのがて…
What is it... It's a cooling type. Ah, yeah, yeah. Mint-like feeling? No, not cooling, cotton candy is the opposite, cooling is the weakness...
あー！ じゃあドリアン…ドリアンだっけ？ サクサクしてる感じで美味しい。ドリアンどう？どうぞ！
Ah! Then durian... Was it durian? It's crispy and delicious. How is durian? Go ahead!
あめ残ってるまだ。まだ残ってるの？ 一緒に行こね、一緒に行こね。
Candy is still left. Still left? Let's go together, let's go together.
一緒に行こうね。一緒にいこう。かんぱい？かんぱい、一緒にいこうね。うわあ！
Let's go together. Let's go together. Cheers? Cheers, let's go together. Whoa!
うわっ…どう？大丈夫？くさっ！くさが出た！
Whoa... How is it? Are you okay? Stinky! The stench came out!
ちょっと、ぺっぺっぺ…臭い！臭い！臭い！
Wait, spit, spit, spit... It stinks! It stinks! It stinks!
臭い！臭い！臭い！これじゃダメか。ダメか。死んどる！ポルカが死んどる！
It stinks! It stinks! This is no good. No good. She's dead! Polka is dead!
そんなに…そんなにやばいの？ 分かるよ。
Is it really that bad? I understand.
ああ、なるほどね。なるほど。いや、でもおもてなしすごいわ、これ。
Ah, I see. I see. No, but the hospitality is amazing here.
いやあ、き、君たちやってみる？やってみる？ ベター？そう、出て出る…一緒に食べよう。
Man, do you guys want to try it? Want to try it? Better? Yeah, come out... Let's eat together.
じゃあ、ドリアンキャンディーは悪くないの。悪くないかもしれない。ただ、大きさがな？大きさがさ、もっとちっちゃいほうがよかったかもしれないかな。うん。
Well, durian candy isn't bad. It might not be bad. It's just that the size... Maybe a smaller size would have been better. Yeah.
でもね、見てただけ。ふふふ。
But you were just watching. Hehe.
はい、ということでね、みんなにね、ちゃんととあるものをちょっとほしいんだ、みんなから。
Alright, so, we want something specific from everyone.
え、そうなの？
Eh, really?
プレゼントがありますから！
Because we have presents!
持ってきたよ！
We brought it!
じゃじゃーん！
Ta-da!
そう、なんか今集めてるらしいからね。
Yeah, since she's collecting them right now.
プレゼントです！どうぞ！
Here's your present! Go ahead!
えのぐ！えのぐ！
Paints! Paints!
え、もう付いた？もう付いてるよ！
Huh, it's already on? It's already on!
赤色！赤色！
Red! Red!
やったー！やったー！
Yay! Yay!
あ、じゃあ私あげる？
Ah, then shall I give mine?
もらっていいですか？ほしいか？
Can I have it? Do you want it?
ほしいです！かわいい！
I want it! How cute!
かわいいこれ出たりしな？ほしいです！
It comes out like this? I want it!
かわいい！めっちゃめっちゃ付けてる！
Cute! You're wearing so much of it!
うれしい！
I'm so happy!
よし！は！わー！
Alright! Ha! Woah!
黄色どうぞ！ありがとう！
Yellow, please! Thank you!
じゃあね、さっきの僕のもほしいかなー？
Well then, earlier... do you want mine too?
Give me, give me, give me!
はい、準備いいか？
Alright, are you ready?
え？こわ。こわ。
Eh? Scary. Scary.
みんな何これ？すごーい！
Everyone, what is this? So amazing!
来た来きたー！おー！
It's here! Woah!
すばらしいよ！生さきもね！
Wonderful! Live Saki too!
皆さんはもうこの色でいるからね！
Everyone is already in this color!
うん、ね、じゃあこれで
Yeah, right, so with this...
帰る。いやいやいや！
We're going home. No, no, no!
あと最後にさ、そう、なんかお口直しがほしいな。
Also, finally... Yeah, I'd like a palate cleanser.
まあね、そうだよね。
Well yeah, true.
ベーちゃんさ
Bae-chan...
持ってきたじゃん！やったー！いくぞ！
You brought it! Yay! Let's go!
いや、気になるだろ！気になるだろ！
Hey, you'd be curious! You'd be curious!
ね、別マイトかな？どうかな？
Right, maybe Vegemite? I wonder?
何かな？
What could it be?
なんこの音？なんこの音？
What's this sound? What's this sound?
こわいな！やばいやばい！
That's scary! Oh no, oh no!
何かな？何かな？おめでとうー！
What is it? What is it? Congratulations!
サプライズ！え？この企画サプライズ？
Surprise! Eh? Is this project a surprise?
緊張すぎてもうプルプルしてるプルプルしてる
I'm so nervous, I'm shaking all over!
ちょっと待ってちょっと待って、見せてあげて！
Wait a minute, show it to her!
ね！見せてあげて！すごいでしょ！そう！
Right! Show it to her! Isn't it amazing! Yeah!
あら、ちゃんと書いてあるよ！持ってある！
Oh, it's properly written! She's holding it!
じゃあ、ありがとう！あ、なんかそらちゃんがしてくれるんだ？もしかして！
Well then, thank you! Ah, Sora-chan is going to do it for us? Could it be!
あら、大丈夫？クリームついちゃわないけど。
Oh, is it okay? Won't cream get on you?
わあ！ありがとう！
Wow! Thank you!
え、こんなの食べられない！だから！
Eh, I can't eat something like this! That's why!
はい！あーん！
Here! Say ah!
美味しい！やば！
Delicious! Oh no!
しあわせおやとうとよ！本当ね！
True happiness! Really!
イオフィがみんな持ってるらしい！イオフィ！ホスピタリティフードレビュー！
Iofi apparently has everyone holding it! Iofi! Hospitality Food Review!
サプライズケーキでしたー！
It was a surprise cake!
よかったね。おめでとう！ありがとう！
I'm glad. Congratulations! Thank you!
はーい！おかえりなえす！
Hii! Welcome back!
ギラ、さっきもさ、やばくなかった？えーとね
Gyra, weren't you guys crazy earlier too? Uh...
そのさ、今度さ、ソラさんが持ってくれた。ケーキ？うん、あれ企画で何だっけ？あ、バーニケーキ！です！
That, this time, Sora-san brought us. A cake? Yeah, what was that project again? Ah, Buny cake! Right!
Thank you, thank you for the cake. I really, I really wasn't expecting that. Thank you.
And by the way, do you remember? We were collecting... colors! Can you see? Look, wait a minute, wait.
はい！おー、いっぱーい！Look at that! We have all of the colors! Look at that!
Hii! Oh, plenty! Look at that! We have all of the colors! Look at that!
いやー、ダニ、ありがとね。今日遊べなかったらどうしようかと思って。
Man, thanks, Dani. I was wondering what I'd do if we couldn't play today.
So, I don't know. I mean we have a lot of colors here. Okay, yobby? Eh, shippy? Oh, ga? Sorene, san? Bejan? Porca? Towami? Paisen?
いやー、ぼくさ、ガーテイャ、タピ！タピや、こう、イニコ、キッタ、全部、に、ちゃんぷり、に、いにかいん、どうしよう？えっと、これね、全部になったら、どうなるんだろうね？
Man, I... tapi! Tapioca, like, inico, kitten, all mixed in, what'll happen? Um, what happens when they all get mixed together?
Let's try. Want to try? Want to try mixing all the colors?
U.M.R! ハイ!
U-M-R! Hai!
UMAじゃないよ うまる!
It's not a UMA, it's Umaru!
U.M.R! ハイ!
U-M-R! Hai!
UMAじゃないよ うまる!
It's not a UMA, it's Umaru!
いつだって全身全霊遊び倒せ
Always give it your all and play to the fullest!
もっと もっと 楽しめよ 乙女
More and more, enjoy yourself, maiden!
みんなに気づかれないように
Make sure nobody notices,
いざ、行け!干物妹ライフ
Now go! The Himouto life!
お気に入りのフードかぶり
Wearing my favorite hoodie,
今日も今日とてゴロゴロして
Lounging around again today,
大好物のポテチを手にして
With my favorite potato chips in hand,
パソコンとにらめっこしよう
Let's play a staring contest with the PC!
立てば芍薬 座れば牡丹
A peony when standing, a tree peony when sitting,
歩く姿は百合の花
A lily flower when walking,
誰もが羨む完璧JK
The perfect high school girl everyone envies!
ほら玄関くぐったら変身だ! さあグータラしよう
Look, once I pass through the front door, it's transformation time!
いつだって「食う!寝る zzz 遊ぶ」の3連コンボ
Always the 3-run combo of "Eat! Sleep zzz Play"
ずっと ずっと ゲームは友達
Forever and ever, games are my friends.
お兄ちゃんは厳しいけれど
My big brother is strict, but
きっと きっと 許してくれるはず
I'm sure, I'm sure he'll forgive me!
わがまま放題は「大好き」の裏返し
Acting selfishly is just the flip side of saying "I love you".
U.M.R! ハイ! U.M.R! ハイ!
U-M-R! Hai! U-M-R! Hai!
UMAじゃないよ うまる!
It's not a UMA, it's Umaru!
U.M.R! ハイ! U.M.R! ハイ!
U-M-R! Hai! U-M-R! Hai!
UMAじゃないよ うまる!
It's not a UMA, it's Umaru!
外では猫をかぶり
Outside, I put on a cat mask,
今日も明日も演じるのです
Acting the part today and tomorrow.
大好評の笑顔をぶきに
Using my popular smile as a weapon,
友達にばれないように
So my friends won't find out.
立てば二頭身 座ればまんまる
Two heads tall when standing, perfectly round when sitting,
歩く姿はちんちんちくりん
Short and stubby when walking,
誰でも癒せる愛敬マスコット!?
An affectionate mascot that can heal anyone!?
さあ限界越えるまでパーティナイト! 宴の始まりだぁ
Now, until we break our limits, Party Night! The banquet begins!
気取りで優しい女の子
Even if I try to act like a graceful and elegant girl,
演じてみても
Acting the part,
お兄ちゃんだけはだませない
My big brother can't be fooled,
嫌われたくないもん
I don't want him to hate me.
素直に言えない「ありがとう」
"Thank you" that I can't say honestly,
態度でしめそう
I'll show it through my attitude.
…だぁ! ゼロゲン撤回! ああもういいいじゃん!
...Ah! Retract that statement! Oh well, whatever!
お兄ちゃんなんて知らない! なんつって!
I don't need big brother! Just kidding!
一心同体ふたりでひとつだってそれがきょうだいでしょう?
Body and soul as one, after all, isn't that what siblings are?
一蓮托生ふたりきりの運命共同体
Sharing the same fate, just the two of us, a community of destiny.
きょうだって
Even today,
自由奔放笑いとばせ!
Laugh off the freedom and do it!
もっと もっと 楽しんだもん勝ち
More and more, whoever enjoys it wins!
天真爛漫スマイルで
With an innocent smile,
ぎゅっと ぎゅっと 心を掴みちゃうの
Grip and capture my heart tightly!
やりたい放題は信頼の裏返し?
Is doing whatever I want the flip side of trust?
U.M.R! ハイ! U.M.R! ハイ!
U-M-R! Hai! U-M-R! Hai!
UMAじゃないよ うまる!
It's not a UMA, it's Umaru!
U.M.R! ハイ! U.M.R! ハイ!
U-M-R! Hai! U-M-R! Hai!
UMAじゃないよ うまる!
It's not a UMA, it's Umaru!
ぱりない! 歌謡曲の始まりだぁ
Party Night! The Kayokyoku begins!
よいしょ! よいしょ! 今宵も一緒に!
Heave-ho! Heave-ho! Together tonight too!
外では猫をかぶり
Outside, I put on a cat mask,
今日も明日も演じるのです
Acting the part today and tomorrow.
大好評の笑顔をぶきに
Using my popular smile as a weapon,
友達にばれないように
So my friends won't find out.
立てば二頭身 座ればまんまる
Two heads tall when standing, perfectly round when sitting,
歩く姿はちんちんちくりん
Short and stubby when walking,
誰でも癒せる愛敬マスコット!?
An affectionate mascot that can heal anyone!?
さあ限界越えるまでパーティナイト! 宴の始まりだぁ
Now, until we break our limits, Party Night! The banquet begins!
気取りで優しい女の子
Even if I try to act like a graceful and elegant girl,
演じてみても
Acting the part,
お兄ちゃんだけはだませない
My big brother can't be fooled,
嫌われたくないもん
I don't want him to hate me.
素直に言えない「ありがとう」
"Thank you" that I can't say honestly,
態度でしめそう
I'll show it through my attitude.
…だぁ! ゼロゲン撤回! ああもういいいじゃん!
...Ah! Retract that statement! Oh well, whatever!
お兄ちゃんなんて知らない! なんつって!
I don't need big brother! Just kidding!
一心同体ふたりでひとつだってそれがきょうだいでしょう?
Body and soul as one, after all, isn't that what siblings are?
一蓮托生ふたりきりの運命共同体
Sharing the same fate, just the two of us, a community of destiny.
きょうだって
Even today,
自由奔放笑いとばせ!
Laugh off the freedom and do it!
もっと もっと 楽しんだもん勝ち
More and more, whoever enjoys it wins!
天真爛漫スマイルで
With an innocent smile,
ぎゅっと ぎゅっと 心を掴みちゃうの
Grip and capture my heart tightly!
はい! ともりぎ!
Hi! Tomoragi!
でね ここに あたしは 2...
And here I have two...
あ! Jangan skip dat zo! Jangan skip dat zo!
Ah! Don't skip that zo! Don't skip that zo!
あたしはいくつかの... Pengumuman!
I have a few... announcements!
で、あたし 口が2つあります!
And, I have two mouths!
でね こんどの birthday はだな...
And, for the upcoming birthday...
じゃあ、ちょっと 見てみよう! Iofi 2024 Birthday Goods! Tadaaa!
Now, let's take a look! Iofi 2024 Birthday Goods! Tadaaa!
はい! Bisa dilihat, ini adalah Iofi Goods 2024.
Hi! As you can see, these are the Iofi Goods 2024.
Birthday-nya. Ilustrator-nya... bisa dilihat sampai mana, terima kasih! Kawaii ne!
Her birthday. The illustrator... let's see, thank you! Kawaii ne!
Kampus life, so so. Kampus life. では、まあ詳細をね、ちょっと見ていきましょうか。たーん!
Campus life, so-so. Campus life. Let's check out the details, tada!
はい! イオフとのおでかけ Reversible Tote Bag! Jadi ini adalah reversible... reversible reversible!
Hi! Iofi's Going Out Reversible Tote Bag! Reversible reversible!
Reversible tote bag. Jadi ini adalah, dalam sama luar, guys!
Reversible tote bag. So this is inside and outside, guys!
So jadikan, kalau bosan pakai warna hitam, kalau kalian bosan pakai warna putih, itu bisa di... apa ya, balikin gitulah, guys!
So, if you're bored of wearing black or white, you can just flip it, guys!
reversible なんでね。えっと裏と、あの、中、あの、デザインが...
It's reversible, you see. The back and the inside design...
イオフィと、え、見てください！おそろいのトートバッグですよ！
And, um, look! It's a matching tote bag!
Jadi ini adalah tote bag yang bisa dipakai sama Yofii,
So this is a tote bag that can be used with Yofii,
jadi silakan pakai! Kamu mau barengan ya sama aku,
so please use it! Do you want to go together with me,
jika kamu mau kemana-mana? Iya, jadi bisa bareng.
if you want to go anywhere? Yeah, so we can be together.
はい！次はこれ！おそろいピンバッジ！
Next! These are matching pin badges!
これは直接っと、ね？セットっていうか、3セット...
This is a set of 3...
Matching Pin Badge (Set of 3)
サイズは約H40×W35mm。
Size is approx. H40 x W35mm.
もしトートバッグにつけても、それでもしものコスプレスタイルだったら、これ使っても、大丈夫かなと思って。はい！
Even if you put it on a tote bag, if it's in a cosplay style, it's totally fine to use it!
Jadi kalau kalian mau disimpen di tote bag, atau kalian mau disimpen di mana,
So if you want to store it in a tote bag, or wherever you want,
atau semacam, "Aku pengen cosplay Yofii pakai ini, bisa enggak?" Bisa banget, Bestie!
"Can I cosplay as Yofii using this?" Of course you can, Bestie!
Ini langsung dijual jadi 3, satu set!
These are sold as a set of 3!
Bonus pembelian set komplet merchandise. Ilustrasi: 夜ノみつき
Set Komplet Merchandise Spesial Ulang Tahun, Bromide bergaya Polaroid bertanda tangan.
Birthday merch set, cheki-style bromide card with a handwritten autograph.
Aku tandatangan satu per satu, jadi please stay tuned, thank you!
I will just sign them one by one, so please look forward to it!
Set Komplet Merchandise Spesial Ulang Tahun.
Birthday Merchandise Complete Set.
Ini adalah setnya, ini adalah bonusnya.
This is the set and the bonus.
Tapi ada, tapi ada, masih ada! Let's go to the next one!
And there's more! Let's go to the next one!
Situasi Voice "Waktu Bersamamu" (Bahasa Jepang).
Situational Voice Pack "Time With You" (Japanese).
Kalau aku pengen dengar voicenya doang, nah ini ada. Uh, mendengarkan.
If you want only the voice pack, you can buy it separately.
この配信が終わった後に買うことができます！
You can buy it after this stream ends!
時間があれなので、最後の曲になりました！
Since time is running out, this is our final song!
なので、この最後の曲は、Yofiiのとても特別な、リリースしたばかりの曲です！
This final song is a very, very special song from Yofii, released a year ago!
Yofii's second original song を初めてここでみなさんに聴いてもらいます！So I will sing my second original song first time for you guys in here!
I will sing my second original song for the first time for you guys here!
なので、初めてお披露目するんですよ、Yofiiのsecond original song、ここで。
So I will announce my second original song right here!
Are you guys ready to hear my second original song? Is it? You guys ready? Thank you.
それでは、最後の曲、聴いてください。
Now, please listen to the final song.
思い返したら 沢山あったの
When I look back, there were so many things.
君に貰ってさ、ばかりだったね
I was always receiving things from you.
不安が巡って、頭から離れない
Anxiety swirls and won't leave my head.
そんなこと知らずに、夜は更けていく
Unaware of that, the night grows late.
いつかは朝日がね、登ってしまうから
Someday the morning sun will rise,
永遠はないけれど、それでも明日に願ってる
so even though there is no eternity, I still wish for tomorrow.
here i am ここにいるんだ
Here I am, I am right here,
私を忘れないでね
please don't forget me.
here i am ここにいるんだ
Here I am, I am right here,
今日もずっとそばにいる
I'll always be by your side today too.
季節は巡り、時間が過ぎてもさ
Even as seasons change and time passes by,
私、変わらずに、君を想ってるよ
I will endlessly keep thinking of you.
aku di sini ここにいるんだ
Aku di sini, I am right here,
私を忘れないでね
please don't forget me.
aku di sini ここにいるんだ
Aku di sini, I am right here,
今日もずっとそばにいる
I'll always be by your side today too.
here i am 星の中から
Here I am, from among the stars,
aku di sini, cepatlah temukanku
aku di sini, hurry and find me.
here i am, i am here waiting for you
今日もずっとそばにいる
I'll always be by your side today too.
aku di sini
季節はめぐり
Seasons come and go, turning around...
時が過ぎてもさ
Even as time passes by.
私変わり果てずれ
I remain unchanged,
君を思ってるよ
Thinking of you.
Aku di sini, ここにいるんだ
Here I am, right here.
私を忘れないでね
Don't forget about me, okay?
Aku di sini, ここにいるんだ
Here I am, right here.
今日もずっとそばにいる
Today too, I'll always be by your side.
Here I am 星の中から
Here I am, from amidst the stars.
Aku di sini, 早く見つけてね
Aku di sini, quickly find me.
Here I am, I am here waiting for you.
今日もずっとそばにいる
Today too, I'll always be by your side.